this is kind of like a continuation of
Haec velut quaedam continuatio
last week's episode where we were
Ultima septimana scriptor episode, ubi fuimus
talking about this amazing amazing
de hoc mirabile mirabile
soldering job the Robin did so go so
Job solidatorium ut vadam et non est Marcus
valiant effort it actually described it
non describitur sed fortissime conanti
worked by some kind of television
laboravi in aliquo genere sem
miracle it worked yes Jeff do you
Jeff miraculo quod sic laboraverunt et vos facite
remember way back on episode number 431
Memini retro via plures res CDXXXI
when you recommended that I buy battery
Cum emere suadetur ut altilium
power battery powered soldering iron yes
Etiam pila ferrea imperium glutino amet
do you remember that I do I just want to
memento quod et tu iustus volo facio
say for the record it sucks let's be
dices ad recordum illud lets 'sit sugit
clear that is not the one I had oh let's
hinc est, quod ille me O lets '
be clear don't one's not the same it's
Quod suus non patet idem
not exactly the same model it's a
neque ita prorsus idem exemplar ad quod suus '
battery powered soldering iron
Lorem pila ferrea glutino
mine's great though is it great what is
mea quamquam est magnus est, magnus est, quod
it great for it's great for little
Nam magna magna parva
at-home projects little at-home projects
minus incepta opera domi domi
okay yeah like I will fix lightbulbs you
yeah sicut ego tibi bene figere lightbulbs
know you can just replace them right no
non novi vos can iustus ius pone principes pro eis
how do you fix lightbulbs when um like
fix um quam operor vos amo, cum lightbulbs
you build a new filament out of solder
et fibram de aedificare novum solidaturam
no like I like to tinker so like with
et non sicut ego similis ad tinker cum quasi
Christmas bulbs you know how there's the
Class aptent bulbs scis enim quomodo non est
wires that come in yeah sometimes
Venit aliquando in fila yeah
they'll break and I just don't feel like
et conteram in youll 'iustus non placet
all right you know buying a new one or
totum jus cognoscatis, buying a novus unus
whatever so you put them back together
et sic ea quae vos
no just heat them up put them together
non solum autem illa frigidum pariter ponam illum
and they work great all right I'll put
omnia magno irritant ponam
together some of the kids toys at break
nugas qui a confractus pars una haedos
where they've got a little metal element
Ive 'got a quo paulo elementum metallum
stuff like that so so last week Jeff I
non ita est quasi ultima septimana Jeff ego supellectilem
built this board here and I did a
et fecit in hac tabula hic built
smashingly good job
Job bonum smashingly
oh my Quasimodo man maybe we should pay
O Quasimodo mea reddere debet homo, maybe simus
attention to the 5 volt it looks pretty
V Cor operam ut is vultus pulchellus
good hey that looks better yeah that
heus, quod spectat melius quam bonum yeah
looks pretty yeah that looks pretty good
yeah spectat pulchra, quod spectat pulchellus bonus
and I was using this wireless thing and
et quod per hanc rem, et wireless
I really don't like it and I said to the
Ego vere non placet, et locutus est ad
viewers I really don't like it so I know
Ego scio vere non placet ita viewers
I'm blaming my tools right mm-hmm but I
Im 'stultum quid contra ius tools mm meum, sed hmm
put new batteries in it for the sake of
propter illud novum gravida
the demonstration and still didn't
et non demonstrationem
really heat up very well wasn't really
re vera non optime calor est realiter
working how did you use it though poorly
et quamquam male uti, quanta opus fecit
I am an amateur okay and I am an
Ego sum, an amateur et bene
admitted amateur
admissus amateur
you're learning is that quick heat up
quod velox est calor es doctrina
pretty quick I'd say like 40 seconds
ego similis dicere XL pulchellus velox seconds
mine is like a five-second heat up oh
meum est sicut quinque-o secundum calefac
you and you're showing fine but like I
Ego autem, sicut et tu? praeclaram
would never start using it - five
nunquam satus usura is - Quinque
seconds I let it heat up and then I keep
seconds et illud est frigidum et castigo
the iron working with then I throw the
tum ferri opus mittat
solder in okay lots of advice came in
consilia in multis bene solidaturam
after last week's show
Ultima septimana post spectaculum scriptor
of course we tackle this Sasha yes
hoc etiam aggredi utique Not
you've got your list of comments that
album de comments quod vos Ive 'got vestra
came in first of all I'm gonna start
venit in primo omnium satus Im 'agnus dei
with circuit man's comment yeah circuit
yeah comment in circuitu hominis circuitu
man says it's okay for me to do that
dicit quod vir suus 'okay mihi ut faciam
because they get longer and angrier as
quia iam adepto ut augeretis furorem et
the comments go on no everybody thank
ire non comment in omnibus laudis
you so much for your kindness that was
beneficio vestro tanta fuit
very kind this week circuit man says
ait circuivi genere septem
awesome show and Robbie your soldering
horribilis et ostende te Robbie solidatorium
is better than mine it's good start yay
melius est meus suus 'satus bonum Yay
for someone named circuit man I figure
nam et ego homo aliquis nomine circuitu figure
that you were probably in the know so I
quae probabiliter et ut in quadriduum tolerant
appreciate that very much
Agnosco, diversi generis multa nimis
right Robert Putnam said that soldering
Robert dicitur quod ius Putnam solidatorium
iron is fine but your soldering
ferrum solidatorium vobis autem sit pulchrum
technique is backward why the wipe the
Quare ars absterget retro
hot tip off with the cloth so there's
calidum panno illic 'a tip cum
minimal solder left ideally the tip will
solidaturam minima præsint egressus est voluntatis tip
be shiny use the clean tip to heat
uti hoc modo mundus erit lucidum tip qui inmiserant
whatever you're soldering and feed this
superlinies solidaturam, et quidquid tibi est pascere
solder onto that piece not the soldering
quod solida pars onto non solidatorium
tip right what's happening with your
Quod suus 'tip dextera tua fieri
method is that the solder is oxidizing
modum est signum vîrium esse oxidizing
and preventing any flow to the piece
et praecludit ne usquam aliqua pars in flow
okay all right that makes sense so I did
ut bene omnia recte facit sensum, sic feci
a poor job by touching the solder to the
officium pauper contactus ad solidaturam
hot tip and then touching the tip to the
tetigisset extremum auriculæ ad calidum et
yes okay okay next up from Eiger wold
Etiam purus purus a proximo Eiger wold
firewalled flux is magic pen SMD or
Si sanatus firewalled magicae uel calamum SMD
paste through-hole okay also well I've
bene propter puteum cadet crustulum et tum quia commune aut inmundum
seen I've seen flux right sorry - did I
vidi ego vidi iustum vexatum iacere paenitet - I did
girl won't say something else also said
nec aliquid aliud dicit puella, et ait:
yeah you need some desoldering - tools
yeah Desoldering vos postulo - instrumenta
oh okay - concept first comment is about
O bene - primum comment est de conceptu
the flux so the solder that I bought has
linies solidaturam ita habet quod emit
2% flux so I am a novice I'm not using
II% vexatum iacere me sic Im 'non usura rudis
solder I'm not using flux in addition to
Im 'non usura praeter vexatum iacere CONFERUMINO
the solder
solidaturam
I'm using one with a rosin core right so
Im 'usura una cum iure et resinam proposuerunt core
is that is that gonna help me out is
quod est 'agnus dei esse, quod est adiuva me
that gonna work
opus est agnus
now I understand though from from just
a nunc intelligo etsi de iusta
doing a little bit of research since our
ex quo enim patres dormierunt investigationis facientes exigua,
feature last week that by touching it to
Ultima septimana ut ad feature si tetigerint
the tip first it's hot and I'm actually
cum suus 'calidi et tip primus ego sum
burning off the the the flux before I
off in in diligenter lauabis mihi ardere ante
get to the board right so I'm kind of
et ego ad tabulam ut ius genus
counter printer acting the effects of
printer agens contra effectis
having a flux core right but the solder
iuris habet nucleum solidatura horis
itself has built in flux now if you had
Ædificavit quoque, si ipsum nunc fluens
a flux capacitor you can go back and
capacitor horis posse redire
tell yourself not to make that mistakes
amen dico tibi non errat, ut quae
that's true in the flux core it says 2%
quod verum est in progredientibus core inquit II%
on this a/c 128 D says it's not 2% it
de hoc enim / inquit D c CXXVIII suus 'non illud II%
actually said what does it say there
Quid enim dicit enim verum etiam,
says flux 2% 2% diameter 0.6 and a bunch
Dicit II horis II%% diameter 0,6 et fasciculum
of numbers that I don't know what they
Nescio quid numerorum
mean
medium
next up from Agarwal as well sorry yeah
Deinde tam sollicitus de memini Agarwal
just that you need some D soldering
vos iustus postulo ut D solidatorium
tools GE soldering tools
GE instrumenta instrumenta solidatorium
okay I'm gonna we're gonna come back to
Im 'agnus dei agnus dei bene venerant ad nos
that one okay okay d soldering is like
okay okay d similis est ea solidatorium
I've got boxes of circuit boards and
Ego got tabulæ, boxes de circuitu
motherboards that are dead that I want
motherboards mortuos, qui volunt mihi
to be able to desolder so remove some of
ita removere potest esse pars desolder
the components so that I can then reuse
quod components ut vadam ad dextram reuse
them so it's like getting free stuff
et sic suus 'amo questus liberum supellectilem
from a waste base right right I get some
vastum a dextris et a base rectam aliquam
resistors get some capacitors loads of
Ergo resistor lineatus aliquam capacitors -perinde
capacitors lots of headers things like
capacitors sunt lots of caput capitis ut
that C 128 D says 63 slash 37 solder
CXXVIII C, ut D exacuere vade inquit LXIII XXXVII solidaturam
which has 37 percent flux 37 percent wow
quae est fluens XXXVII XXXVII percent percent wow
that's a lot of flux that's like what
quod suus 'multus of flux quod est simile quod
Wow
wow
okay I didn't even know such a thing
quia bene mihi non est ita
existed well now you do hmm okay and
modo tam bene fuerit et facies hmm
knowing is half the battle wait I know
Scientia media acie scio insidias
better you do better all right learning
doctrinam magis recte facere meliores
here tonight to merge man personally I
hic nocte et ipse hominem iungi
would never use a battery-powered
nunquam utor a altilium-Lorem
soldering iron okay there is too much
ferrum solidatorium nimium bene est
risk of a cold solder joint earth cold
periculo iuncturam terram frigus est frigus solidaturam
solder joints and flaky connection not
et ne pilo tunsum in nexu articulis solidaturam
that we encountered any of that not that
offendit, quod illius quis enim non
we encountered any of that during our
nos offendit, quod in quolibet nostrum
feature as the battery drains and if you
ut si pila pluma exhaurit
do a lot of soldering good luck finding
non multum bona fortuna inventum solidatorium
the bad joints right as Robert Putnam
est malum quod rectum articulis Robert Putnam
stated the technique is to heat the
Quod autem dictum est quod ars est
joints and touch the solder to the
in articulis tangentibus ferrumen
underside of
subtus
the iron well in place on the joints
ferrum quoque loco in artus
okay the solder should flow nicely on
ut bene parte solidaturam super influunt subtiliter
into the connection be careful too much
et facient in nexu nimis
solder and it will flow out the other
et factum solidare non influunt ex altera
side of the board and you have a glob of
ex parte tabulam habes glob
solder that can cause a short if the
solidaturam hoc non potest facere si in brevi
solder balls up instead of flowing the
pro fluit ex balls ascendit solidaturam
joint isn't hot enough so do you think
Non ita putes satis iuncturam calidus
that that's all it is is that I'm just
quod sit omne id quod sum,
not I'm not heating up the joint first
Im 'non, non calefacit usque ad primum iuncturam
like if I actually if I bring this up
huius bring up, si tamquam si actually
for you so let's get a look here so
sic lets 'vultus vobis adepto de hic et
let's get a look at one of my terrible
lets 'adepto per vultus procul unus qui meo infelici
joints and get so I'm gonna get out the
ut Im 'agnus dei adepto sicco ut mollirent artus,
same wireless soldering iron I'm just
ferrum solidatorium eiusdem wireless sum,
gonna take 45 seconds so lean it no I
agnus dei nititur, ut non sum XLV et seconds
haven't cleaned it I've got I've got
Non purgari factum Ego got Ego got
this wire thing but now it was mentioned
hoc nunc est quod dictum est filum
there that we need to get like a sponge
non quod opus est ad modum spongiae
or something to to actually clean it off
Redige is off aut quod est in actu,
now I've got this like wire cleaner that
Ego iam got is quasi filum, quod lautus
I've seen people use and I thought hey
Ego vidi populi uti dixi heu
that's cool dollar store sells those so
quod suus vendidit eos et frigus copia pupa
hey that works right and it does work
recte operatur et facit ui
but it's not a wet sponge right so if I
sed suus non ita infectum, si recte implens spongiam
heat this up is it going to make a
usque ad illud quod est frigidum facere
difference let's get some of my 2% flux
difference lets 'adepto mihi in aliquibus horis II%
solder and let's see how this goes
melius est videre quod solida
alright so I'm going to heat that right
licet ius non ita Im 'iens ut succenderetur
up first let's use this one because this
et quia hic primum uti
one looks like I didn't get any solder
qui vultus amo non adepto ullus solidaturam
on there whatsoever p1 so what they're
et quæcumque sunt in p1 quod tu
saying is heat that up right and let
quia rectum est verbum calor et lux
these let's get some heat in there then
In æstus scriptor aliquam est haec ergo tunc
you let the the clen into the heated
et in calore dimisistis clen
area so you don't heat it let's
illud lets vos operor ut regio tantum potest calefacere
straighten up my solder there and let it
et ita derigimus meum ibi solidaturam
draw it in
trahere
okay mmm
bene mmm
oh there's the flux oh yeah oh okay Wow
yeah heu heu heu bene illic est fluxus Wow
oh you did it what a diff made that
O quantum fecistis illam diff
looks really good Thank You Sasha what a
Tibi gratias ago tibi spectat vere bonum ad quid Sasha
change from your attitude last well then
tum etiam ex ultima mutare habitus
so I hate to be Captain Obvious
Captain Speculum est ita odi
what does the battery powered unit work
Quid enim opus est unitas powered altilium
does it work yes yeah and I put new
yeah, quod sic posuit operatur et ego novi
batteries in it for the sake of the
propter illud gravida
demonstration rat last week absolutely
Ultima septimana omnino rat demonstrationem
okay it does like I had it turned on so
ut bene sit tibi non fuisse illud et Convertétur
I feel fit I feel vindicated okay
EGO sentio sentire fit bene te deprehensam
viewers thank you so much this is part
gratias ago tibi, hoc tantum pars viewers
of what I love about category 5 TV
genus circa ea quae amant V TV
versus other webcast other TV shows is
TV ostendit, est alterum versus alterum webcast
that we're very we try to be very
quod nimium esse cupiunt
interactive and this is an opportunity
haec facultas Interactive
for you to to teach us and in so we're
nam et in ut docere nos, et sumus
kind of bringing that about and bringing
portantes de genere istum
it back to the viewers as well so
reversus est ut visorum
hopefully this is a good learning
Utinam sic bonarum literarum
experience for all of us that's true
experientia nos omnes esse verum
next up so Shaun White any channel of
Paulo deinde ut in omni alveo sumpserant Alba
this says amazing five five five episode
haec dicit prodigiosus res quinque, quinque, quinque,
episode five five five last week nice
nice quod res quinque, quinque, quinque, postremo septem
work
opus
amazing tech tips love the micro tech I
mirabilis amor tech tips in Micro tech me
smell espionage tactics nope that is
Nequaquam ita inquisitio consilium capiam
flux it says well done after 555
Unde bene secundum fluxum DLV
episodes still by far the best tech show
tamen multo optima TV show tech
out there and a lot keep up the amazing
ibi multum mirabile sustentet
work Wow thanks Shaun so even when you
Curabitur Vivamus agens operatur ubi etiam
have a horrible soldering job we're
officium habent similitudinem solidatorium sumus
still the best thing 5 was amazing and
optimus res eram prodigiosus, et tamen V
p1 was great yes so just a now that
Etiam ut magna a nunc P1
you've got the solder working imagine
nunc demum istaec nata solidaturam working meditati
how more amazing five five six is gonna
quo magis mirabilis quinque, quinque, sex sit amet
be oh five five six we've already shown
in quinque, quinque, sex o weve 'iam ostensum est
you right how good five five six is
quinque a dextris et quinque sex bonum
right JME was five five five a
erant quinque, quinque, quinque a dextris JME
coincidence I'm about where Robbie is
accidit circa me ubi est Robbie
with this stuff and soon you'll find out
et mox huic supellectilem youll 'reperio sicco
that five five five is a somewhat
quod est quinque, quinque, quinque, aliquantum
special number in beginning intermediate
peculiari numero in medium beginning
electronics
electronics
I did not know that the timing circuit
Morbi cursus quam nesciebam
555 no that was entirely unintentional
Quia nulla omnino est praeter intentionem DLV
last week just ya know we we've been
Ultima septimana iustus ya, scire non habuimus
doing the show for every single week for
omni septimana pro uno ad spectaculum facere,
555 weeks
hebdomades DLV
specifically so specifically so that
et in specie secundum speciem, ut
Robbie could do a miserable soldering
Robbie facere a miser solidatorium
job with a miserable tool that's what we
quod officium cum miser tool ut '
been working toward like everything led
Sicut adduxi super omnia operatur
up to that moment no we didn't and we
nec non et nos in tempore
didn't intend how that wasn't a plan
non quo id animo non consilii
well we just needed a baseline soldering
sicut et nos quoque opus a baseline solidatorium
job from you so that we can get that so
Vos can adepto a officium ut ita ut
that now we can see on episode 1055 how
MLV quo modo quod non possumus videre res in
far Robbie is count exactly and and it
Robbie longe est et prorsus, et numerare
would be a robot in my place yeah yeah
locus esset, in robot est yeah yeah
next up V to veto Jojo CR some comments
deinde quaedam in V C. Marcius Ralla Jojo Comments
on your soldering to make some
in solidatorium ut de
improvements ok so here we go once again
Nunc ergo eamus improvements ok quondam iterum
showing how the community comes together
showing quo communitas adunatur
and is directing us and giving us
et duce et dare nobis
feedback that is going to improve our
feedback quod est iens ut amplio nostra
soldering job
job solidatorium
yes so number one use lead-based solder
Sic igitur ex numero uti plumbum ferrumen
unless you want it to fail ok your
ok quod tibi deficere, nisi tuum
solder and iron can also work at lower
ipsamque deorsum ferri potest operari
temperatures with lead-based solder ok
ok solidaturam secundum temperaturas cum plumbum-
that's interesting I didn't know that
ut 'interesting et nesciebat quia verum est
the reason there's a couple of reasons
causas nulla ratione duorum
that I switched from LED now here in
iam hic in me switched a DUXERIT
Canada I cannot get I can't get approval
Canada possum non possum non probat
to sell devices that I create if they
quod si creare est vendere cogitationes
contain lead solder right so I decided
Habemus plumbi continere statui ferrumen
to change to let free because I do
quod sit liberum facere, ut mutandi
intend to eventually get to the point
animo eventually adepto in puncto
where I'm good enough that hey some of
heus Im 'ubi satis quod aliqui
the things that I'm building can be
quae in me potest esse aedificationem
sellable right we're not there yet don't
recte tamen facere non sumus sellable
worry I'm not selling anything joints
Im 'non vendere articulis solliciti aliquid
could be yours
non erit tibi
earlier when see 20 ad said 6337
XX dicitur videre, cum mane ad (VI)CCCXXXVII
yeah that's the tin lead ratio so that
Yeah stagno plumboque ratio est ut quod
wouldn't work ok if I see if you're
ok, si opus esset, non video, si vestri '
gonna be ok so that's that's one of the
Bene ergo de hoc quod amet
reasons yes for more views but for if
causa est, quod sic plus views sed si
you're gonna resell it you can't use
tu amet uti non potes esse resell
that
quod
but for hole right you should be fine
sed dextera essetis fine foraminis
okay so there's two other reasons I
ut illic 'alius bene duabus de causis te
don't have good ventilation that's
quod suus 'non bonum evacuatione
reason number two so I don't want to be
ita quod dualitas nolo esse
breathing it in I don't want to feel
halitus in me, non quomodocumque sentire concupiscamus
like the Mad Hatter great hobby but I
Gloria magna est amat, sed quasi Hatter
don't I don't really need cancer right
ne non vere postulo ius cancer
now and so I'll learn with lead-free
Et nunc discere et sic ex libero plumbum-
I'm happy with that good call third
Im 'gauisus per ut bene tertio vocationem
reason kind of stems from that but also
Quod autem ex hoc genere
my kids I really want my kids to
Ego vere vis ad meus kids meus kids
participate and so part of it is getting
ut aliquam partem accipit
their hands on the sod or getting in
manus ulmisque officio
there and we're using lead-free solder
et ibi erant 'usura plumbum-liberum solidaturam
so that I don't feel worried that my my
sic ut sollicitus non sentiunt meus mihi
10 year old is putting his fingers in
X annos natus posuit in digitos
his mouth after soldering something with
quod ex ore suo post soudando
a let let course right so there's a
et sic a dextris quidem occasione
couple of things there so absolutely
et omnino quae duobus ibi
sure LED lead-based solder may be better
ducatur, certe plumbum secundum solidaturam sit melius
for some uses especially in you know
quia utitur quibusdam praesertim in scitis
professional soldering jobs but I think
Ego autem jobs solidatorium professional
for me I'm gonna stick with the
Im 'agnus dei me cum lignum unum,
lead-free so we just got to make it work
perducat nos got ut libero operetur
right okay number two yeah point number
yeah illud recte bene numerus duo est numerus
two you don't add the solder to the tip
duo non addere ad tip solidaturam
until you've heated up what you're
tu es enim ad succenderetur fornax
soldering then and only then you have
tunc ergo habes et solus solidatorium
the solder thank you okay so uh yeah
solidaturam gratias ago tibi, ut bene uh yeah
Marsh man commented on that as well so
Ita quoque homo qui commentati in pastu paludis virecta
yes excellent point and we proved
Et sic optimum iam probavimus,
tonight that Dottie is a very good
Optime autem nocte Dottie
comment right number three if you put
Si recta commendet numero trium posuistis
the solder on the tip you need to clean
solidaturam super tip vos postulo ut mundatis
it off just like that except everything
nisi eam quae sicut
that you did you need to undo Robbie I
non ut vos postulo ut solve fasciculos Robbie
heard you saying thinking that yes so
dicentes quod sic cogitandi et non audivit vos,
the longer the solder is on the tip of
diutius in faucibus ferrumen
your iron the more flux you destroy oh
O quanto perdes fluxa ferrea
just what I was saying yes and I
et quod sic modo quae fuerat dicens
probably it was in my head because of V
probabiliter esset in propter capitis V
- Josie R's comment right having read it
- R scriptor comment Josie autem recte legit illud
earlier mm-hmm very interesting and good
hmm ante mm, valde interesting et bonum
point that I'm actually burning off the
illud quod off ego tamen perurebat
flux yes which is going to cause issues
quae causa est, quod sic vexatum iacere ad quaestiones
with my solder joint absolutely and I
cum solidatura iuncturam et absolute,
understand that so that's cool and then
Intelligo et ita quod est frigus
keeping in line with that whoo flux is
Si sanatus observatio in linea cum whoo
your friend
amicum tuum
it helps solder the helps the solder to
solidaturam hoc adjuvat in adjuvat ad solidaturam
connect to your components he says as a
sicut dicit components ad coniungere
bonus tip but I'm bomb please watch my
sed obsecro bomb tip bonus sum spectare meum
solder and where you make an attempt to
solida et ubi conatus
put these what please watch some better
Quid melius vigilare haec placere
people solder before you make an attempt
et antequam solida temptandam
that's soldering on TV hey come on now
Nunc autem venit super TV solidatorium ut 'heus
come on okay so let's back up and talk a
et sic bene dic age retro
little bit about what category 5
V, quod de exigua genus
represents and and first before I get
Et primo refert, et non ut prius
into that I want to tell you and
Ego volo tibi dicere, quod et in te
everyone viewing never let someone tell
Non ergo aliquis dicere omnibus viewing
you don't show what you are learning
quid horum non praestes
don't write no never be afraid
nolite timere neque scriberem nihil
to fail never be afraid to show that I'm
ostendam, quod nunquam deficere timere ad me
not good at this I'm learning and the
Ego autem ad hanc eruditionem non
reason I say that is because I think if
causa est, quia non dicunt, quod si putas
we all need to achieve this excellence
Omnes opus ad consequi tantam eminentiam
before we're willing to share it with
Cum enim sumus coram tribuere communicare
the world then category five wouldn't
tunc non esset genus quinque orbis terrarum
exist I'm proud of you oh this is really
Im 'vere non est hic, o cor vestrum
that's a really great message just right
nuntius ingenti per quod vere iustum
across the whole globe it's what
quae per orbem est
category five represents like we started
genus repraesentat, ut nos coepi quinque
with a webcam and we stepping-stone dour
stone webcam, cum superscandens vigilum et duram vomer
way up yeah and we're looking at
yeah et usque ad quaeritis
stepping stones tonight and and along
Erg saxa perque noctem
that line never ever feel that way you
neque sentiunt, quod semper est recta via
need to be able to fail and you need to
necesse est posse deficere, et opus est
be able to do it in the public eye and
posset facere illud quod in publica oculus
it's okay it's okay to have friends that
suus 'suus' okay okay ad se amicos
love it and it is absolutely and it's
et amare illa sit omnino et illud
cool to learn and I love this show
frigus ego amare discere atque hoc spectaculum
because I can I can learn with you and
quoniam ego vobiscum sum, et non potest scire possum
we can learn together and and I
scire possumus simul et ego
appreciate your comments and we're we're
Tibi interdum commentarios bene sumus sumus
learning together I get a pretty good
doctrina et simul a pulchellus bonus
solder joint there yeah yeah how many
solidaturam communem non memini quot yeah
times have we done episodes where you're
tempore quo tu fecimus episodes
programming something oh and it fails
Aliquam libero, et quod utinam non
yeah it just goes horribly wrong but
sed nefas est modo memini
that's part of what makes the show great
quod magna pars facit
is because some of those shows are the
quia quaedam sunt spectaculis
greatest shows to learn from shows you
Maximi cognoscere ostendit
watch it you go oh my goodness I've made
et custodiet te, o mi bonitas Ego feci
the same mistake real - well yeah and
idem error verus - et bene yeah
there are a lot of great shows yeah and
ac spectaculis multa memini multum
we're not just CG we're there a lot of
non enim sumus sicut erant CG multum
great shows on YouTube and on the on
Juvenis in spectacula et magnis
television that they figure everything
omne quod instar television
out beforehand and they do it when it's
et ante eos feceruntque suus
perfect
perfectus
yes and so then I as the layperson feel
Sic igitur et in istis sentimus
like I I'm not at that level I can't
sicut et ego non sum non possum in eo gradu
achieve this I can't try this yeah let's
hanc assequi non memini scriptor
start here and let's work our way up
lets 'satus hic et laboro usque nostris
together you know to be honest it wasn't
et non scis amet
pretty but it worked it worked like you
sed satis est quod laboraverunt laboraverunt similis tui
did it I did it I did it
Ego autem non feci ita sum eam
go team yeah all right thank you for the
gratias ago tibi ius bigas ut totum pro yeah
comment I appreciate that
Agnosco, non commendet
so c128 d yes first has said recently in
et quod sic primum dixit nuper in d C128
the chatroom that you need to use
Vos autem necesse est ut quae chatroom
separate flux paste if you're using
Si vos erant 'usura fluunt separatum crustulum
lead-free okay so important so let me
et deduc me momentum libero purus
get this straight even though I have a
hoc ut linea, etsi non habent
2%
II%
flux core in my solder so I thought oh
core vexatum iacere in cogitavi ut venias solidaturam
well it has flux built-in so I don't
bene autem facere ut constructum- in fluxu
need to buy flux are you telling me I
opus emere a me ventris tu vera mea
need to go out and buy flux paste so
et necesse habeo exire, et emere vexatum iacere crustulum
that I can add that to my solder joints
quia quod potest addere ad solidaturam compagibus
before I heat them up that is that the
Et hoc est quod frigidum est in conspectu eorum
idea right c128 is he is here with us
bonum est nobis hic ratio C128
live we'll move on with yours right
tecum vivere, puteus 'permoveo in dextera tua
shouldn't come back to your response to
Non revertemur ad responsionem esset
that question okay so see 128 D also
quaestio, qui ita bene et vide D CXXVIII
says Robbie you don't need to spend a
Robbie dicit non necesse est ut expendas
lot of money to get a decent soldering
multam pecuniam accipere honestum solidatorium
iron all you need is one that plugs into
ferrum omne opus quod plugs in
a wall outlet and runs off of AC current
off exitus, et fugit in muro current ex AC,
any of the Weller line would work out
de industria linea Weller
quite well for your needs and are
bene propter necessitates sint, et satis
reasonably priced just select one that
pretium recte eligere unum tantum esse
is between 20 and 40 watts Amazon
quod est inter XX XL Amazon Watts
carries them for about fifteen to twenty
portat ad quindecim ferme
dollars fifteen to thirty dollars us not
triginta quinque pupa pupa nos
sure what that isn't Canadian rupees and
certus ut qualis non rupias et Canadian
they do an excellent job welder Weller
Weller optimum faciunt officium welder
so I can't say this daughter daughter
Non possum dicere hoc et filiam filiae
sold there's an element we're gonna get
Ibi suus 'agnus dei adepto quod venundatus sis ut elementum
one of our biggest fans is gonna say
dicit unus ex nobis maximus fans sit amet
it's solder no it's solder it's solder
suus 'nusquam solidaturam suus' suus 'solidaturam solidaturam
yeah I'm just always gonna try and say
Im 'agnus dei yeah sicut semper et dicere tentant
so
ita
Weller soldering station normally
Weller solidatorium statione Northmanni
started about $100 u.s. okay getting one
bene nobis de $ C est questus started
of the regular irons now and having it
ferro et regularis habere iam
as a backup when you can afford the
quasi in tergum potest esse cum
soldering station wouldn't be a waste of
superfluum esset statio glutino
money either
vel argentum
yeah the iron is more portable and less
yeah quibus ferrum ignitum plus et minus portable
of a hassle for a quick and dirty repair
a REMORDEO ad a velox et sordida instaurabo
for a quick and dirty repair than the
parumper velox et sordida quam aedificaverunt
station is but the main thing is that
nisi quod pelagus illud est, quod station
just about any AC powered soldering iron
iustus de aliquo Arcana Coelestia powered ferrum solidatorium
will be better than a battery-powered
melius fore quam altilium-Lorem
toy be sure to use 60-37 solder it's
exsisto certus ut suus 'toy 60-37 solidaturam
better for electrical work than 60/40
melius electrica opus, quam 60/40
okay see 120 ad you set it without
CXX ad bene video quod non eriges
saying at stepping stones right because
dicendo quod conculcarent saxa
in my mind I'm thinking I need a
ego cogito animo meo opus
soldering station I need the I need the
Mihi opus est opus in statione solidatorium
at least the entry level of the best
optimo certe viscus campester
right right bang on my friend this is
Amicus meus est fortissima right
what it's about is finding that stepping
quid suus 'quod sit gradus invenire
stone so cheap battery-powered doesn't
et lapis cheap non powered altilium,
really do a very good job the batteries
vere non a valde bonus job in eu gravida
don't last long the batteries don't last
motum haud diuturnum fore, non ut in eu gravida
long enough for doing a good size
magnitudine satis benefaciens
project no so that's why it's good for
Non est bonum consilium quod quid est
small things for like a quick like two
veloces quasi pro duobus parvis
joints yes and then your
et quod sic articulis tuum
done now I love what c128 D pointed out
Quid ego feci dictum C128 D
here that you can get away with just a
quod hic vos can iustus adepto evacuandam
standard soldering iron which is a big
ferrum solidatorium quae vexillum est a magnus
step up from this little guy but not
Hoc parum guy sed non est a step
going to cost me the amount of a my
Ad cost mihi moles mea est
dream station so I can pack my way up to
Non possum sic statione somnium meum usque ad stipant
that soldering station great but right
Glutino bonum est magnum gradum
now I can get started with something a
posse cum aliquid a nunc incipiat
little less very cool and I did know and
ego cognovi quod minus frigidissima
I did you do first let's look at David
Et tu noli respicere ad David primi lets '
fear okay David fear says get one of
ut bene David dicit unus ex timorem timorem
these and points us to a link to a $70
haec ostendit atque nos nexum ad LXX $
OLED programmable soldering iron
Ferrum solidatorium OLED programmable
okay on banggood very cool but still $70
sed etiam valde frigus bene in banggood $ LXX
so I may as well look at the hundred
ut videre licet quam centum
dollar soldering station at that point
Conticuere omnes intentique ora statione pupa solidatorium
it's starting to get a little bit close
incipiens suus 'propinquus ut exigua
to the price and recommends as well that
et in pretium etiam suadeo ut
we look at 63 37 or 6040
LXIII XXXVII at nos aut (VI)XL
leaded solder going back to my comments
solidaturam, plumbátis cæsa reversusque ad comment
so based on largely what c128 Dee said
et late secundum ea quae dicitur Dea C128
about being able to start with something
circa quod non possit incipere
cheap and work your way up and then
et ascendit et operari viam vestram cheap
still use that old one as just for the
uti vetus tamen illa est sicut iustum est
little drink the tinkering here and
tinkering huc paululum bibere
there told it works and then based on
ibi mihi et secundum hoc operatur
reading what David fear sent and saying
quae misit et timor legis David dicens
hey yeah we can do that I got on Amazon
heu yeah possumus facere quod got in Amazon
and you can head on over to cat5 dot TV
et TV possunt caput in super ad apicem CAT5
slash solder kit and it arrived already
et iam pervenit ornamentum preliari ferrumen
so obviously available on Prime and I
manifesto ergo praesto est primus et ego
picked one of these up let's see and it
levavit oculos istorum ut videamus
is way microscopic compared to what I
minimum hoc modo quod comparari
was expecting I was expecting from the
expectante expectante et ex
picture but this was going to be like a
Hoc erat quasi imago
full size toolbox right that's it's like
Mutationes conlatae plenum ius mole quod suus 'similis
a mini like a mini toolbar yeah okay
Mini Toolbar in mini sicut bene yeah
let's get this out of the way so that I
Hoc lets 'adepto ut me de medio fiat
can show you folks that so this was the
et folks qui non potest hic est
next step from this this cost me $30 now
proximus huic gradus ex hoc nunc mihi mercede constant $ XXX
I'll tell you see 120 ad you mentioned
Et dices ad CXX videtis pro qua locutus es
like the 16 dollar Weller's and things
sicut et de rebus XVI pupa Weller
like that I got on Amazon I started
EGO coepi EGO got in Amazon quod simile
looking around and the cheapest that we
aspiciens circum atque, ut vilissimum
could get here in Canada was $22
abesse non in Canada fuit XXII $
Canadian and it was not brand name and
Et factum est nomen eius et ne notam Canadian
it was just a cheap soldering iron right
Glutino bonum ferri vili Erat
so
ita
why I went with this kit it's only eight
ob hoc profectus ornamentum est octo
dollars more it came with the box
et factum est cum pupa ultra arca archa
it came with extra tips and it came with
quod factum est ad extra tips et factum est cum
some extra essentials so let's get in
ut in quibusdam extra necessitatem, sic lets '
here and this is going to also take us
et huc ad hoc ut sit nobis:
back to our Wald's comment about having
nos back to comment circa habens de Wald
solder D soldering tools right okay
bene D ius tools solidaturam solidatorium
let's get in here so into the box boom
hic sic lets 'adepto per in a buxum BUTIO
first and foremost a solder sucker oh
imprimis quae stirpibus exit O solidaturam
there you go is that for excess solder
inde est, quod pro vobis excess solidaturam
oh that's fun it also pinches your face
oh ut 'fun te urgeret illum et faciem tuam
is that for excess like this is for
est, quod sic est in excess
removing solder so you can heat up the
Movens igitur solidaturam, ut possis calefac
solder and then suck up okay got so that
Bene autem solida et sugunt quod
you can remove chips and things and
et omnia potes et removere eu
reuse or fix when you mess things up so
Quae cum ita statuere Donec vel reuse
that if if you ask me that's worth
quod si pretium ut 'si a me
probably the extra eight dollars anyway
octo extra probabiliter usquam dollars
it came with a whole bunch of solder now
Factum autem est totum fasciculum ferrumen
what is this lead-free solder wire
ferrumen molestie libero sit ipso plumbo
perfect this is 2.0 flux 20 20 gauge no
2.0 perfectum est nec fluxus XX XX METIOR
a zero point eight millimeter versus my
nulla in parte me octo versus millimeter
zero point six that I have here so
sex sunt quae nulla parte hic est
similar to what I have but it's got a
Quod suus 'got a me et similis
lot yeah 20 grams I guess that is okay
EGO coniecto yeah XX of P. hoc est bene amet
so it's got this itty bitty tiny tool
et suus 'got hoc instrumentum minima itty bitty
box
arca archa
how cute is that all right it's got a
Cute quod suus 'got ut recte
box with in there what do we have and
In arca archa cum nihil habeat, et quid possumus
remember this was only $30 so okay what
memento quod tantum $ XXX tam bene quam
do you expect for $30 it's got a little
exspectas ut suus 'got a $ XXX minus
stand that is basically just a cheap
sta pertinet quod sit iustus cheap
little tray right with a couple of nuts
parum recto alveo duorum nucum
that hey you you can hold your soldering
Heus tu, qui potes habere glutino
iron oh yeah and it's got a sponge that
O Yeah quod ferrum et hora accepit spongiam
you can wet to clean it so I didn't have
Redige te potest infectum esse quod non est ita
one of these now I do so that's cool
id unum tantum modo frigus
but it's not as nice of a holder as my
sed suus 'nice quod non est de me ut possessor
helping hands so I'll probably just end
ut youll 'iustus terminus probabiliter tate manus adiutrices apponat
up using my helping hands anyways but if
per manus autem mea auxilium, si tamen anyways
you don't already have helping hands
rationem non habent, manus auxilium
that's something anyway it's in the box
quid est quod usquam in arca
kind of thing okay what else have we got
bene habemus aliud genere
we've got a couple of a couple of
Comperto autem de duobus copulabis
tweezers
forcipe
these are anti-static and I like that
haec sunt-stabilis et anti placet
the tweezers that I have have become
VOLSELLA facti sunt mihi
magnetic so I needed new oh really
O vere sic magneticum opus novum
yeah so it's a pain because I'm working
yeah et dolor suus 'quoniam Im' opus in
with little itty bitty resistors and
Puer et parum bitty Resistors
they're magnetized to the songs which is
hi erant qui carmina in vi magnetica imbuebam
really really hard
vere vere ferreus
then we've got the soldering iron
Comperto ergo quod ferrum solidatorium
obviously but a couple of extra things
manifesto autem ad res extra duobus
that came in the kit it's got D
ornamentum id esse factum in D 'got
soldering wire that's cool
solidatorium filum, quod est frigus
soldering desoldering wire I can put
Non possum posuit solidatorium Desoldering filum
this on all those bad joints that I made
Haec omnia membra malis feci
right and I can remove I can touch this
hoc jus transferam tangam
to it and heat it up and it will suck in
et calefac sursum ad eam, et erit in lac filio
the solder absorb it and then I take it
ergo signum vîrium esse absorbet et sumam eam
away and the solder is off of the joint
auferat et non vigilat ad iuncturam parte solidaturam
no yeah so I need this when I correct
yeah, non opus est ut hoc corrigere cum
the soldering joints yes I've created
Ego ita creatus est in articulis solidatorium
okay then I've got my soldering tool
Ego got bene et instrumentum solidatorium
here you go now what is what really
Hic tu ergo quid est quod realiter
excited me about this and Dave fear
et timuerunt me excitarit Dave
pointed it out on the one for $70 let's
quis enim indicavit de $ LXX lets '
actually bring this up through the
huius bring up per actually
magnifier the through the microscope so
et ad maiores magnificantem microscopiis,
you can see what I'm seeing here it has
vos can animadverto quis Im 'cum hic habet
a temperature gauge and it goes from 22
caliditas XXII de METIOR, et vadit ad illam
part me from 200 C all the way up to 450
C ad CC ab omni parte carere mei usque ad CDL
and it's just a dial so for a cheap
et sic suus 'iustus a dial pro cheap
little thing that's pretty good look at
At hoc satis exiguus
what else we've got
quid aliud Comperto
it does go up to 60 watts so it's a
ut iret usque ad LX non ut suus 'a Watts
pretty you know it's gonna heat up
suus 'agnus dei calor satis nosti eum
pretty quickly yeah apparently should do
Yeah celerius videtur facere
a pretty good job we'll see we'll see I
hoc est officium satis bonum youll 'animadverto ut youll' animadverto ut
mean we're gonna be checking it out on
erit reprehendo is sicco in nobis sit amet
future demonstrations and seeing how it
cum et futurum quomodo demonstrationes
works so but then it also came with one
sed etiam ut cum eo operatur
two three four five two extra tips so
duo eget sapien ut duo tria quattuor quinque
we've got some extra tips there that
Comperto quod est aliquid extra tips
came with this and each one is a little
cum hoc unusquisque modicum
bit different for different jobs you're
aliquantulus diversis in diversis jobs vestri '
going to expect that as I grow and learn
Ad illud quod expectes, et crescere discent
how each one works then that's going to
quippe quod quisque deferretur
be cool so if I remove this I can see
et hoc removendum frigus erit, si non potest videre
there's my tip well so you just slide
tip bene mihi non supplantabuntur tantum ut vos
and then it's got a ceramic core so the
et sic deinceps obtinuit tellus Core
ceramic core apparently I'm learning is
Videtur quod Im 'eruditio tellus core
very quick to heat up yes and so that's
et quod sic tam velox nimis calefac ut '
a good thing I have a hair straightener
Bona res EGO have capillus straightener
that's similar oh yeah that's good I
id quod est bonum tibi similes utinam yeah
like that it has the adjustable
sicut quod habet Populus Novifacta Quotidiana
temperature mm-hmm
hmm mm temperatus,
and it does have also an inline power
et potestatem non habet etiam quod inline
switch which was an added bonus because
quod addatur bonus quoniam transibit
you normally have to unplug one of these
soles haberet unum unplug
kind rights soldering irons so it's a
Glutino bonum est ius quoddam ferri illud
good start I think this is a great
Ego puto hoc est bonum satus magna
little thirty bucks yeah and it's
minus triginta leones memini suus
available in our shop now cat5 TV slash
CAT5 tabernam iam available in TV VULNUS
solder kit now I've been able to get
Ego autem potuerant ad ornamentum solidaturam
obviously it's available here in
suus 'available hic in manifesto
as you see it here it's also available
Hic quoque est videre quod suus 'available
in the United States as you see it here
ut hic vides in Civitatibus Foederatis Americae est
in the UK they don't have exactly the
in the UK ad non habere exacte
same kit but I found one that's very
set hoc ipsum quod non inveni
similar and it's only 14 pounds so man
XIV libras similis, et sic suus 'tantum homo
you can check that out and it even has a
Vos can reprehendo et hoc etiam habet
couple of extra things in the UK but I
De duobus quae sunt extra me sed in the UK
obviously can't test it because it's a
id manifesto potest probare, quod suus 'a
little bit different but it looks like
modicum aliquantulus diversis: sed is vultus amo
about the same thing and it is what it
quod idem est ac
is it's a cheap soldering iron but it's
Glutino bonum est quod ferri non est vilis
better than what I have and it's ready
parata habeo melius suus
to get me started exactly and I liked
coepi prorsus ad me, et ego probaverunt
that it came with all this extra stuff
hoc autem factum est per universam supellectilem quae extra
that I'm going to need anyways for my
Im 'non iens ut postulo anyways meum
projects and just a cheap little case
et si iustus projects uiliter minutatimque
which appeases might need to have
quae placat tibi, ut debeo
organization because otherwise
quia aliter organization
everything just sits in a cardboard box
quae iusta sits in cardboard buxum,
is it a quick cool solder iron as well
tam facile est frigidum ferrum ferrumen
well I haven't plugged it in yet but I
sed tamen non tam in SUPERGESTUS
don't expect so no okay I didn't read
non exspectare ut nihil non bene legere
anything about it being anything special
quod est circa ens aliquid specialis
yes yeah it is quick to heat up yeah
yeah ita sit velox ad calefac yeah
which is good yeah but I can put it in
quod est bonum, sed non possum posuit in yeah
my my helping hands turn off the power
auxilium meum mihi manibus averte virtutem
switch which I guess is gonna help
EGO coniecto cuius est auxilium switch amet
anyways because being able to turn off
quia non potest declinemus ad anyways
the power switch and turn it back on and
et transibit et potestas avertet eam
it's got quick heating then should work
inpatiens operabitur tunc suus 'got calefactio
pretty well but we will find out on a
sed satis bene de hoc invenies in
future episode how much better that
quanto magis quia res futuras
works then my my old battery-powered
operatur et mea meae altilium-Lorem
soldering irons so you don't want to
solidatorium ut ferro non vis
miss some of the features that we've got
deesset aliquid eorum quae Comperto
coming up and do check out that Kit Kat
Lorem ut ascenderet et Kit Kat
5 TV slash solder kit now I know it is
V TV VULNUS ornamentum solidaturam hoc modo novi illum
just a cheap kit it's gonna get you
cheap suus 'agnus dei adepto vos iustus ornamentum
started it's going to improve our game
nos coepi ut amplio ludo suus 'iens
it's gonna help me to do a little bit
suus 'agnus dei mihi ut faciam exigua,
better when it comes to soldering and
quod cum fit, melior solidatorium
some of the things that we're learning
ut quaedam discis
here on category 5 technology TV is
V hic genus technology in TV est
really helpful as well if you've got
tu quoque si utile realiter got
comments you want to share with us
commento participes vis nobiscum
comment below or head over to our
et sub commento super caput nostro
YouTube channel on our website category
YouTube channel in nostro genus
5 TV if you're watching on cable TV
V, si vos vigilo TV in funem TV
there are so many different ways that
tot modis
you can interact with us we'd love to
et nos youd 'amo ut vos can penitus per nostrum
hear from you and love to find out what
et amor a te audire quae invenire
what we could do better
quid facere bonum
[Music]
[Musica]
[Applause]
[Plausus]
you
vos
[Music]
[Musica]